<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maker in Residence</title>
    <link>http://mir.rijnieks.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maker in Residence</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Krisjanis Rijnieks 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 11:30:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://mir.rijnieks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://mir.rijnieks.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 11:30:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mir.rijnieks.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is here to document the Maker in Residency residency by Krisjanis Rijnieks at the Chester Beatty Library in Dublin. Krisjanis Rijnieks is an artist working with creative coding, projection mapping and digital fabrication. During the residency Krisjanis will hold several Projection Mapping with the Raspberry Pi workshops for kids and adults, as well as create a projection mapping installation at the atrium of the Chester Beatty Library building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The residency is happening between 5th and 18th December of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://mir.rijnieks.com/post/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 10:11:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mir.rijnieks.com/post/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good day. This is my first post regarding my residency at the Chester Beatty Library in Dublin, Ireland. The residency starts next week and there are still a lot of things to prepare for it. During the residency I will give several Projection Mapping with the Raspberry Pi workshops and build a projection mapping installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very excited about the upcoming workshop at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tog.ie/&#34;&gt;TOG hackerspace&lt;/a&gt; next Monday, 5 December 2016. It is going to be an introduction to the world of projection mapping through Raspberry Pi and open source software. Follow TOG to not miss detailed information about what time it is going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I am very excited about the residency. I like the concept of the Maker in Residence programme which is also about opening museum spaces for makerspace and hackerspace activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>